# Gregory Lemieux, Computational Engineer

gregory.lemieux@gmail.com | 1.510.847.6519

GitHub

#### SUMMARY

Astronautics professional with a broad technical backround working towards Computational Engineering degree. Excellent communicator within commercial, manufacturing and research environments; Proven ability to adapt to changing responsibilities based on evolving project requirements with a diverse skill set developed through participation in multiple stages of spacecraft design, development, and operations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SSL - Systems Engineering Specialist

2012-04 — Present

http://sslmda.com

- Developing next-generation orbit simulation code for controls design and analysis.
- Responsible for the next-generation on-board flight software orbit estimation filter.
- Founding member of the Guidance, Navigation and Control Software Development Working Group.
- Produced mission analysis tools for the NASA Restore-L to help guide hardware subsystems decision-making.

# Space Science Laboratory - Research and Development Engineer 2008-06 — 2012-04 http://www.ssl.berkeley.edu/

- Developed science data accumulation forecasting tool to aid in planning mission critical science collection.
- Integrated DSN Service Scheduling Software into active mission operation scheduling process.
- Scheduled ARTEMIS mission supports including critical Lunar Orbit Insertion.
- Contributed to the Deep Space Network Scheduling Advisory and Mid-range Management Groups.

#### Janos Technology - Opto-mechanical Engineer

2003-12 — 2006-05

http://www.janostech.com/

- Designed infrared lens assemblies for commercial, defense, and research applications.
- Represented the engineering department as a member of the company-wide Quality Control Committee seeking AS9100 compliance.

#### Center for Space Physics - Mechanical Engineer

2001-09 — 2003-06

https://www.bu.edu/csp/

• Designed and developed the vacuum-sealed opto-mechanical assembly for the main science payload for the SPIDR NASA mission proposal.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## SSL Commercial Geosynchronous Spacecraft Orbit Raising Considerations http://www.univelt.com/book=5817

2016

 $\circ~$  Survey findings from all SSL launches since the 1990s.

#### **THEMIS Mission Networks Expansion**

2010

https://arc.aiaa.org/doi/10.2514/6.2010-1934

 Discussion of the integration of the Deep Space Network software and processes for the ARTEMIS mission extension.

#### **AWARDS**

#### Asterism Award, SSL

2015

 Peer-to-peer recognition for developing and delivering introductory training material for new orbit dynamics group employees.

### Apogee Award, SSL

2013

 Received for contributions to a 2013 NASA Institute for Advanced Concepts (NIAC) proposal for a deep space communications architecture concept.

## **ARTEMIS Project Recognition, Space Sciences Laboratory**

2010

• For contributions to the Lissajous and Lunar Orbit Phases.

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

#### **UUCB - Social Media Team**

2018-07 — Present

#### https://uucb.org

• Administrative member of the church Social Media Team. Responsible for training, technical support, and analytics reporting to the church Program Council.

## **UUCB - Safety Implimentation Team**

2017-09 — Present

http://uucb.org

- Responsible for educating all church program groups on the Safety Plan requirements.
- Trained Family Ministry and Religious Education Volunteers on Emergency Evacuation procedures.

**EDUCATION** 

Purdue University 2016-09 — Present

M.Sc. - Interdiscplinary Engineering, GPA: 3.2

Stanford University 2015-06 — 2015-08

- Introduction to Linear Dynamical Systems (EE263)

Santa Clara University 2014-09 — 2015-05

- Linear Algebra I (AMTH 245), Linear Algebra II (AMTH 246)

**Boston University** 1997-09 — 2002-05

B.Sc. - Aerospace Engineering, GPA: 2.98

......

SKILLS

Scientific Programming: Matlab/Simulink, Julia, Python, C, Fortran

Source Control: Git, SVN

Operating Systems: Linux, macOS, Windows

.....